Hi, I'm here with Pete Koomen, who's a cofounder of Optimizely.
大家好 有请 Optimizely 的联合创始人 Pete Koomen
Pete, could you tell me a little bit about what Optimizely does?
Pete 你能简单告诉我们 Optimizely 是做什么的么？
>> Yeah, we make it easy for our customers to optimize and
好的 我们帮助我们的客户优化
personalize the experience they give their customers on their web site or
他们的客户在访问其网站或使用移动端应用时的体验
mobile applications.
并提供更个性化的服务
>> Fantastic, and
非常棒
what's one of your favorite memories from early on at Optimizely?
那在 Optimizely 的早期 你有什么最美好的记忆么？
>> There are a lot.
有很多
I think probably the one I'm most proud of is when we helped
我觉得我最自豪的一次 可能是我们帮助
the Clinton Bush Haiti campaign raise a lot of money for
克林顿布什海地基金会为2010年的
earthquake victims in 2010.
地震灾民筹集了大量的资金
So Dan, my co-founder, and I were coming off the back of two startup failures,
那个时候 我的联合创始人 Dan 和我刚刚经历两次创业失败
and we had just started working on Optimizely, and
正着手创立 Optimizely
we were building an easier way to run A/B tests on your website.
当时我们正在找在你们网站上进行 A/B 测试的更简单方法
And a few weeks into the project, we got a call from somebody on a newly
刚进入项目几周 就接到一个新机构的电话
set-up organization, the Clinton Bush Haiti Fund that was created to try and
克林顿布什海地基金会 它的宗旨是
raise money for the victims of this horrible earthquake in Haiti.
帮海地大地震灾民筹集善款
And they had one beleaguered IT guy I think who built this website and
当时他们只有一个 IT 人员 负责开设网站
was struggling to keep it up.
并挣扎着保持网站运营
And they were getting hundreds of thousands of visitors every day.
但是当时每天有数十万的访问者
And they called us because they had worked with Dan on the Obama campaign
他们打电话给我们 是因为他们曾经与 Dan 在 2008 年奥巴马竞选时合作过
in 2008 and they wanted to improve the website.
他们想要改善这个网站
They wanted to earn more money for these earthquake victims from the website.
他们希望能够通过这个网站为地震灾民筹集更多的钱
And so over the course of several days,
所以那几天里
we barely slept at all, we built the beginnings of our platform and
我们几乎不睡觉 建立了我们平台的雏形
then we ran a bunch of A/B tests on their website.
然后对他们的网站进行了大量的 A/B 测试
What I mean by that is that we took a look at their website, and
也就是仔细检查他们的网站
came up with hypotheses of how could we make this better.
然后考虑怎么能够帮助它改进
And maybe it's adding an image of earthquake victims next to the credit
比如说在信用卡表格旁边加上地震灾民的图片
card form, or changing the layout, or making the text more readable.
或者是改变版面 或者选择更易懂的文字
And after a whole bunch of these experiments, we were able to measure
在结束大量实验后 我们就可以计算出
that this particular change actually improved the conversion rate.
某个改变到底能增加多少转化率
This one harmed it.
这个对转化率有害
This one improved it.
这个能提高转化率
And we were able to actually raise their dollars per eyeball,
最后 我们可以让 10% 的网站访问者
essentially, by 10%.
捐出善款
And so we actually helped them raise an extra million dollars for
我们实际上帮助地震灾民
the victims of the earthquake.
额外多筹集了一百万美元
>> That's incredible.
非常了不起